

Yang, Bo

Developer

3

+1-415-420-9693



https://yang-bo.com



pop.atry@gmail.com



pop_atry



yang_bo



955091



Atry

About me -

I am a developer who knows how to create application frameworks.

I founded various open-source projects for creating micro-services, neural networks, reactive GUIs, and DSLs, which are stared 3000+ times on Github.

My current interesting is machine learning engineering or development in functional programming languages, especially for creating developer tools or frameworks.

Skills —

Scala

Machine Learning

Software Design

Agile Project Management

Hack *5.5 Haxe *5.5 OpenCL *5
DevOps *5 ActionScript *4
C++ *4 Java *4 JavaScript *4
Rust *4 OCaml *4 Testing *3
C *3 Spark *3 Akka *3

(*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness) to 6 (Expert).]

Open-source projects

2021-2022 HHVM C++/Rust/OCaml is Meta's virtual machine running Hack. I ported the open source branch of HHVM to Nix and created CI pipeline for building, testing, and packaging HHVM.

Since 2018 Dsl.scala Scala is a framework to extend Scala language features in libraries. I also ported this framework to Haskell as Control.Dsl.

since 2016 DeepLearning.scala and Compute.scala are libraries for creating complex neural networks.

since 2015 Binding.scala Scala is a reactive templating language for creating web and desktop GUI.

2015-2016 Microbuilder Haxe / Scala / Java / JavaScript is a toolkit that helps you build system across micro-services implemented in various languages communicating via RESTful JSON API.

since 2012 haxe-continuation Haxe

provides async/await syntax for Haxe.

since 2010 protoc-gen-as3 ActionScript3

is a Protocol Buffers plugin for ActionScript 3.

since 2007 other 100+ of open-source projects

Publications

2017 DeepLearning.scala 2.0: Statically Typed Neural Networks2017 More than React

2009 Adobe Flex 3: Training from the Source (translator)

Talks

2017 Deeplearning. Scala ——Thoughts and practices on open source deep learning framework DBTC 2017 Monadic Deep Learning Strange Loop 2017 **Neural Networks & Functional Programming** ArchData Summit · Beijing 2016 More than Async QCon · Beijing 2015 Specific-domain extension in an universal language ECUG Con

Experience

2019-2022 Meta Platforms Inc Software Developer I built machine learning infrastructure to detect fraud in payments and integrate it into various products. Then I moved to Hack/HHVM OSS team, maintaining HHVM's open

various products. Then I moved to Hack/HHVM OSS team, maintaining HHVM's open source branch.

2015-2019 Thoughtworks Inc Senior Consultant / Lead Consultant

I maintained some open-source projects sponsored by ThoughtWorks. I also took the role of consultant or technical leader in various delivery teams for creating mobile and web applications and data platforms.

2014 Shenzhen QiFun Network Corp., LTD Chief Programmer I led the Q-Force Team in developing game engine along with its related tools, and two mobile games.

2011-2013 Shenzhen Putaoteng Network Technology Co., Ltd. Co-founder I led the start-up team in developing a 3D side-scrolling game engine VinyHome and a social game Nan Da Nu Pei.

2008-2011 NetEase, Inc. Chief Programmer I participated in various product teams as a developer or the technical lead, includ-

I participated in various product teams as a developer or the technical lead, including Zhan Guo Feng Yun (web game), Ka Pai Dui Jue (web game), Deepcold (3D game engine).

2007 Beijing HiPiHi Information Technology Corp.,Ltd Software Engineer I developed variant components of both client-side and server-side for a 3D virtual world, HiPiHi World.

2006-2007 Beijing AutoNavi Software Co., Ltd. Software Engineer As a developer, I developed some components for a 3D navigation software.

Education

2002-2006 Southwest University of Political Science and Law Bachelor Of Laws